ORIGINAL WORK BY TATSUYA ENDO SERIALIZED ON SHUEISHA'S SHONEN JUMP PLUS
(遠藤達哉原創作品 連載於集英社《SHONEN JUMP PLUS》)
It seems like the targets have entered the room. There are three of them.
聽起來目標已經進入房間,有三個人
The ones in the back are hefty in size.
後面兩個的身材應該蠻高大的
They're standing away from windows and doors.
站的位置離門窗有段距離
Their footsteps tell me that they're pros.
從腳步聲來判斷,這些人都是專家
Conrad sat down on the couch against the wall.
康拉德坐在靠牆的沙發上
Hand over the goods.
好了,東西交出來
We'll pay you after that.
先驗貨再付款
You better keep your promise.
你一定要遵守約定
Yup, this is the MNG data.
沒錯,是MNG的資料
Then, as promised...
那按照先前的約定...
- They made the deal. - All right, let's go in.
-確認交易 -好,我們進去吧
- Yuri. - Roger!
-尤利 -知道了!
State Security Service.
國家保安局
You're under arrest for suspicion of espionage.
現在以間諜嫌疑罪逮捕你們
Dammit!
可惡!
Out of my way!
少擋路...
Good evening, piece of trash.
晚安,人渣先生
I have a lovely cell reserved for you,
我已經幫您訂好豪華牢房
so please come with us to the station.
所以請您務必大駕光臨
MISSION:28 PART A: MISSION AND FAMILY
劇名:任務:28 A Part:任務與家人
Good work, Lieutenant Briar.
做得好,布萊爾少尉
Thank you.
多謝誇獎
This is your next assignment.
這是你下一項任務
Are you aware that there are some books and articles from the west
你知道西方有些書跟文章
that mock and ridicule Ostania?
在奚落東國嗎?
The contents are all vulgar things like fabrications and conspiracy theories.
那些東西的內容都很低俗 要不是捏造的,就是陰謀論
Most of them are sold to the west
大多數都是透過東國
through an underground publishing company in Ostania.
一家地下出版社賣過去的
THE REAL OSTANIA: INSIDE THE DEVIL'S REPUBLIC
(東國的真相:未知的魔鬼之地)
And this name surfaced from among
在那些寫手中
the writers.
我們查到了這個名字
Franklin Perkin, 39 years old.
富蘭克林柏爾金,39歲
During the past administration, he was a newspaper journalist
在前政權時期,他是名報社記者
but he was arrested for stirring up the anti-government extremist groups.
後來因為 煽動反政府的激進份子而遭到逮捕
Tail him, gather evidence, and catch the people buying his works.
盯住他,收集證據,連買家一起抓住
Although these are stupid articles,
雖然這些文章內容很離譜
there are tons of idiots in the west who will fall for it.
但是西方就是有笨蛋會相信
Get rid of it before it begins to affect the public opinion.
在影響公眾輿論前,解決他
Aren't you overworking, Yuri?
這樣你工作不會太多嗎,尤利?
Don't worry about me!
不用擔心我!
This man is making money by degrading his own country.
這個人透過貶低母國來賺錢
Just the thought of someone like this breathing the same air as my sister,
光是想到這種人 跟我姊呼吸著相同的空氣
makes me sick.
我都快吐了
Observation of J-095, Franklin Perkin.
監視對象J095,富蘭克林柏爾金
On the 6th, the subject wakes up at 7:21, and watches Good Morning Ostania.
六號早晨,目標於7點21分起床 收看《早安東國》節目
The subject curses at the newscaster.
並咒罵新聞播報員
At 8:10, the subject leaves for his job at the post office.
8點10分,目標出發去郵局上班
See attachment for details of his attire.
有關服裝詳情,請見附件
The subject rides on the third car of the U-8 train.
目標搭上了U8線第三節車廂
See attachment for description of fellow passengers.
有關同車乘客詳情,請見附件
At 12:06 p.m., the subject goes to the restaurant Fjord with coworker M.
中午12點06分 目標與同事M前往費約爾德餐廳
He orders the set lunch A. See attachment for the conversation topic.
他點了A套餐 有關對話主題,請見附件
At 5:49 p.m., the subject leaves work and goes to the central market.
下午5點49分
The 12th Global Education Symposium was held today.
今天舉辦了第十二屆全球教育座談會
Sonia...
索妮雅小姐...
At 7:33 p.m., the subject returns home,
晚上7點33分,目標回到家
and watches the shows: News 20, and Berlint In Love after dinner.
用完晚飯後,收看電視節目 《新聞20》以及《伯林特戀曲》
Infatuated with the female lead.
很迷戀女主角
-Why? - Because I love you!
-為什麼? -因為我愛你...
No notable activities until he retired for the night.
直至夜間就寢前 沒有注意到特殊活動
- You did thorough research on this man. - You can count on me!
-你調查得還真是詳盡 -包在我身上吧!
You've been doing this for two days without any sleep.
你已經通宵兩天工作了吧
Take shifts so that you can rest.
跟別人換班,好好休息一下
This is nothing.
這沒什麼啦
Here's the report for the following day.
這是隔天的報告
On the 7th, at 8:07 a.m., the subject left for work.
七號早晨 目標於8點7分出發去上班
Ordered set lunch B at Fjord.
在費約爾德餐廳點了B餐
Fjord.
費約爾德
Yor.
約兒
- You're exhausted. Take a rest. - No, this is my usual self.
-你累了,去休息吧 -沒有,我跟平常一樣
Mr. Perkin! Mr. Perkin, I know you're in there!
柏爾金先生! 柏爾金先生,我知道你在裡面
- Hey, landlady. - Hurry up.
-房東太太 -快點
Give me your unpaid rent!
把欠我的房租拿來!
Can you give me a little more time?
您能不能多給我一點時間?
You said the same thing last time!
上次你也說過一樣的話!
Day after tomorrow! I'll pay you the day after tomorrow.
後天!後天我就付清房租
If you don't, I'm definitely going to kick you out this time!
你再不付錢 這次我鐵定會把你趕出去!
That damned landlady.
該死的房東
Dad, I'm going out for a bit. I made dinner so make sure you eat it.
爸,我出去一下 晚飯我做好了,要記得吃
Okay. Bye.
好,拜拜
Does he suspect he's being followed?
他發現自己被跟蹤了嗎?
Or he's looking for something to write an article about.
還是他在尋找寫作的素材?
In response to this, our country
針對這件事,我國
must take a firm stance!
應擺出堅定的立場來應對!
That's right! Make those in the west pay for this!
沒錯,讓那些西方人付出代價!
I can't get anything worthwhile.
都拍不到什麼好東西
My parents got me this Bondman pistol!
我爸媽幫我買了這支彭德曼的手槍!
Wow! I'm so jealous! Let me borrow it!
好棒喔,真羨慕你!也借我玩嘛!
- No way. - You're so stingy.
-才不要 -小氣鬼
Hey!
等...
My pistol!
我的手槍!
Destitute street children
貧窮的街童
rummaging through garbage for scraps. Not bad.
在翻垃圾找人們不要的食物,不錯嘛
Why did you do that, old man?!
臭老頭,你這是幹什麼?
I'll tell on you to the Secret Police!
我要跟祕密警察告狀!
You're a little miser who hoards wealth and refuses to share with others.
不想跟他人分享財富的小吝嗇鬼
Someone like you with ideologies of the west
腦袋裝著西方意識形態的你
will end up getting arrested, and killed.
才會被逮捕處刑喔
- That jerk! I'll kill him! - Stop it.
-混帳!我要處決他... -別衝動
Leave him be until we get the buyer from the underground publishing company.
在找到地下出版社的買家前 不能對他出手
This article will be a hoot!
這篇文章一定會紅!
Frank.
富蘭克
Dad.
爸
You're not taking on dangerous jobs again, are you?
你不是又跑去做什麼危險的工作吧?
Of course not. Stay away.
當...當然沒有,你不要過來啦
If you weren't so stuck on your sense of justice,
要不是你當初那麼堅持什麼正義感
you could've held on to your newspaper job.
現在說不定還是一名記者
What's wrong with trying to
想讓家人生活的這個國家
make this country a better place for my family to live in?
成為更好的地方,這樣有什麼不對?
Even now,
就算是現在
money is still necessary to support a miserable life like this.
為了維持這樣窮酸的生活 錢仍然是不可或缺的啊
If we had money, Mom could've...
如果有錢的話,媽當初就...
- Frank, you... - Forget it! Dammit.
-富蘭克,你... -當我沒說,該死
On the 11th at 8:36 a.m., the subject leaves for work.
十一號早晨 目標於8點36分出發去上班
He hasn't made any suspicious
不管在家裡或是外出時
contact or communication with buyers at home or during his outings.
他都不曾有過 可疑的聯繫舉動或是與買家通訊
In that case...
這樣的話...
It must be at his workplace.
一定是在工作的地方
All this mail has been inspected, so it's ready.
這些郵件都檢查完畢了,那就麻煩囉
Thanks for your hard work.
辛苦了
Mr. Joseph, I'll take care of it.
約瑟夫先生,我來就好了
- Go ahead and take your lunch break. - Thanks!
-您先去午休吧 -謝謝了!
What should I eat today?
今天要吃什麼好呢?
He was mailing his articles after the inspection check.
避開檢查之後再寄出自己的文章
Once you send that,
一旦寄出去
you'll become indefensible.
你就無法為自己辯解了
On the 15th at 8:02 a.m.
十五號早上8點2分
I'm going to work.
我去上班了
State Security Service.
國家...保安局
Sorry Dad, I might not be back for a while.
抱歉,爸 我可能有一陣子都不會回來了
Franklin Perkin.
富蘭克林柏爾金
You wrote this, am I correct?
這是你寫的,對吧?
We've already arrested the buyer who you sent this to. So just give up.
我們已經逮捕了收件的買家 所以束手就擒吧!
You guys were courteous enough to wait for me outside?
你們竟然這麼好心在外面等我?
I never knew the Secret Police could be so kind.
原來祕密警察也蠻貼心的
It's to prevent your family member from seeing you in a pitiful state.
這只是為了不要讓你的家人 看到你悲慘的模樣罷了
Don't get the wrong idea.
不要會錯意了
I fought against the government, but you're just their dog.
我與政府為敵,而你們是政府的走狗
I wonder who is more pitiful.
不知道誰更悲慘呢
I will never do anything that would cause distress to my family.
我不會做出讓家人傷心的事
Never.
絕對不會
I'll submit an application so that your father can get some assistance.
我會幫你申請補助 多少能貼補你父親的生活
That'll be a big help.
多謝了
Hey there, Yuri!
這不是尤利嘛!
- Director! - I heard you did a very good job!
-局長閣下! -聽說你這次大顯身手喔!
- That makes this old man very happy. - I'm honored.
-大叔我很高興呢 -這是我的榮幸
The workload must be tough for a rookie.
這種工作量對新人而言很辛苦吧
Don't get too stressed out.
別給自己太大的壓力喔
I'm okay. I think I'm suited for this job.
不會,我認為我很適合這份工作
I'm going to keep up this pace, and catch Twilight
我要憑著這份氣勢逮捕黃昏
to keep this country safe!
保衛母國安全!
I see. That would be nice.
這樣啊,真能這樣的話就太好了
I'll treat you to a delicious steak one of these days.
過兩天我請你吃好吃的牛排吧
Really? I'll have you keep that promise!
真的嗎?局長不可以失信喔!
Coming!
來了!
Hey, Sis!
嗨,姊!
- Yuri, what are you doing here so late? - Uncle.
-尤利,這麼晚了,你來做什麼? -舅舅
Good evening, Yuri.
晚安,尤利
Why are you here, Loid Forger? You should work nights too!
你怎麼會在,洛伊德佛傑? 晚上也給我去上班啊!
Did something happen?
發生什麼事了嗎?
I just wanted to see your face all of a sudden.
我只是突然想看看姊姊的臉
What is it, chihuahua girl?
幹嘛,吉娃娃丫頭?
You worked hard today. I'll make some tea.
今天工作辛苦了,我去泡茶
Sis.
姊...
Sis!
姊!
- Ugh. - Yuri, you'll disturb the neighbors.
-好噁 -尤利,你這樣會吵到鄰居的
MISSION:28 PART B: THE ELEGANT BONDMAN
劇名:任務:28 B Part:華麗的彭德曼
My name is Bondman!
我的名字是彭德曼
- Leave things here to me, and go, Agent M! - No!
-剩下的就交給我,特務M! -不要!
I don't want to lose you!
我不想失去你!
- M. - I'll follow you wherever you go, Bondman.
- M... -你去哪我都要跟著,彭德曼
Let's make our escape!
那就一起逃吧!
My sophisticated suit.
講究的西裝
My beloved shiny silver car.
心愛的銀色閃亮轎車
My highly-skilled techniques and gentlemanly behavior.
高人一等的實力跟紳士的舉止
You're so cool when you drive!
你開車時好帥喔!
I love you, Bondman!
我喜歡你,彭德曼!
I'm super cool and clever.
我英俊瀟灑又智力超群
So love is just inevitable.
當然免不了談場戀愛
I'm a spy for a country that's in a hostile relationship with yours.
我是間諜 我的國家與你的國家是敵對關係
If you get in my way, I will kill you.
敢擋我的路就殺無赦
How ridiculous.
真是荒謬
We're the same species living on the same planet.
作為生存在同一個星球的相同物種
Why should we fight because of some borders?
何必要為了什麼國界互鬥?
If you really believe that, why don't you stop this conflict!
你真的這麼認為的話 為什麼不阻止這場衝突?
This concludes our peace treaty!
和平條約簽立了!
There are no more walls that can separate us!
再也沒有高牆能夠分開我們了!
You're amazing, Bondman! I will never leave your side!
你好厲害,彭德曼! 我這輩子都不會離開你!
Papa is obsessed with developing bombs!
我父親沉迷於開發炸彈!
Please put a stop to it, Bondman!
拜託阻止他,彭德曼!
Sure thing, Gina!
沒問題,吉娜!
Thank you, Bondman!
謝謝你,彭德曼!
I'll introduce you to Papa once he wakes up.
等爸爸醒來,我就把你介紹給他認識
I'm glad, Gina.
我真是高興,吉娜
My terrorist boyfriend
我那個身為恐怖份子的男朋友
was arrested because of you! I'll never forgive you!
都是你害他被捕的!我絕不原諒你!
Revenge is futile. I'll make you forget everything with my love.
復仇是空虛的 我會用我的愛讓妳忘掉仇恨
The objective of our organization is world domination!
我們組織的目的是統治全世界!
Enough of that, let's go on a date.
那種事不重要,我們去約會吧
Mr. Bondman, please pay this month's rent.
彭德曼先生,請付這個月的房租
And the neighbors are complaining about the noise.
還有鄰居在抱怨聲音太吵了喔
You're beautiful as always, landlady.
房東小姐今天也很漂亮呢
- Who are all these women? - You're a player!
-這些女人是誰? -你這個花花公子!
Choose one!
給我選一個啊!
- How many women are there? - You're a cheater!
-你到底有幾個女人? -你這個騙子!
I will bring happiness to every lady in this world.
我要把幸福帶給這個世界的每位女性
Basically, dealing with danger is part of the job as a spy.
身為間諜,危機處理是工作的基本
Spy Wars! Next episode is, "Revival of Bondman!"
《間諜大戰》下一集,彭德曼復活!
I see. This is what people call a lovey-dovey story.
我明白了 這就是所謂的卿卿我我的故事
I can talk about this with Becky.
我可以跟貝琪聊這個
- Anya is all grown up now. - Stop it.
-安妮亞現在是大人了 -勸妳不要
When did this guy ever show gentlemanly behavior?
這傢伙什麼時候有過紳士的舉止了?
PART C1: BONUS 1: THE HEART OF A CHILD
- 劇名: - C1 Part:附錄 1: 童心
ON THE ROOFTOP OF A DEPARTMENT STORE
(在百貨公司的屋頂上)
Anya wants to ride the polar bear.
安妮亞想要騎北極熊先生
I don't understand what's so entertaining about this.
我不懂這個有什麼娛樂性可言
This mysterious polar bear. Why do kids want to ride on these?
這隻神秘的北極熊 為什麼小孩都想騎這種東西?
It's boring and lacks stimulation.
既無聊又不刺激
Is it a reforming device created by
這是獨裁政府打造出來
the dictatorial government to rob emotions
用來奪取乘客情感的改革裝置
from its passengers and make them into mere puppets?
好讓這些人變成全然的傀儡嗎?
I want to ride it!
“倫”家想要騎!
We should let her ride it, Loid.
讓她坐吧,洛伊德先生
REVERSE
(反向)
Was it fun?
好玩嗎?
I want to ride it again!
人家想再騎一次!
I don't understand kids!
我真搞不懂小孩!
PART C1: BONUS 2: THE HEART OF A CHILD
- 劇名: - C1 Part:附錄 2: 童心
The Silt Beach is filled with many beachgoers.
席爾特海灘滿滿都是海水浴遊客
Anya wants to go to the beach.
安妮亞想去海邊
I can't take you to the beach, but I can take you to a pool.
我不能帶妳去海邊,游泳池倒是可以
Pool!
游泳池!
I'm glad she's having fun.
看來她玩得很開心,真是太好了
Oops, I peed.
糟了,不小心尿出來了
-But I'm sure no one will know. - Ooh, I feel relieved now.
-算了,反正沒人會知道 -解放了好舒服啊
BE GOOD AND DON'T IMITATE
(好孩子不要模仿哦)
I'm never going to a pool again.
我再也不去游泳池了
What? But she was having so much fun!
什麼?她那時不是玩得很開心嗎?
I don't understand kids.
我真搞不懂小孩
PART C2: BONUS 3: WAKING UP
- 劇名: - C2 Part:附錄 3: 鬧鐘
Damian.
達米安大人
You have to wake up or you'll be late for roll call.
快起床,不然要錯過早點名了
What?
咦?
- Damian! - You were awake?
-達米安大人! -你已經起床了?
Yeah, since an hour ago. I was studying.
對啊,一小時前起來的 我剛才在念書
I overslept once but that was just a one-off.
我之前曾經睡過頭 但那種事只會發生一次
- I see. - You never disappoint!
-這樣啊 -真不愧是你!
Wake up, Anya! You only have ten minutes before the bus arrives!
醒醒,安妮亞! 校車再十分鐘就要到了!
The bomb will explode in ten seconds.
炸彈再十秒鐘就要爆炸了
Anya will make sure to stop it.
安妮亞一定會阻止的...
I'm begging you! Get up!
求求妳,快起床啊!
You'll get a Tonito if you're late to school too many times!
遲到太多次會拿雷電啊!
SHE WAS LATE
(遲到了)
LOST
(尋貓啟事)
MISSION:29 PART A: THE PASTRY OF KNOWLEDGE
(任務:29 A Part:智慧甜品)
PART B: THE INFORMANT'S GREAT ROMANCE PLAN II
( B Part: 情報商的戀愛大作戰II)
Subtitle translation by: Lili Morita
字幕翻譯:洪貞韻